December 24th, Stellar Year 2149
Welcome back!
Welcome home.
I'm so happy you're back safe!
It's important to get off the
front lines so you can rest.
I got you all gifts.
Man, the year just flew by!
This is your second Holy Birth Festival!
I'm happy that this time,
I got to give you your presents!
I'm home.
I'm happy for you.
Yeah.
Time for a party!
Are your arithmetic drills done?
Your punishments always teach me so much.
Independent Mobile Force...
Basically it means we kick Legion ass,
like we've always done.
Yes, this is a proposal from me,
as an individual,
to grant your request
to fight on the front lines.
The issue is the foreign officer
who will serve as your commander...
I'm okay with it.
Fine by me.
Yeah.
Yup.
Shin, what do you think?
Western Theater forces
sustained 60% losses.
We're speeding up the curriculum
at all our officer training schools,
specialist training schools, and boot camps
to replace the lost manpower.
But they won't have the training they need.
And while the Legion
lost their combat forces,
their manufacturing facilities are unharmed.
The war situation's only going to get worse.
So unless something changes,
humanity will be slowly worn down
until we finally lose, correct?
Yes.
We'll maintain our defense lines,
as we have been doing,
while putting together
an independent mobile unit
that can bring concentrated firepower
down on critical Legion areas.
I didn't expect you to put together
the same plan we had.
A mobile strike force comprised
entirely of Eighty-Six...
If you'll forgive my saying so,
this doesn't sound like you.
Sure, but they're the ones who wanted it.
They have their own values.
I don't have the right to refuse them
out of misplaced pity.
If they still choose the battlefield
after all that's happened,
I'd like them to be able to stay together.
Will the Eighty-Six accept
this foreign officer, though?
I talked to them already.
I was worried as well,
but I guess I shouldn't have been.
After all...
This is from me.
Thank you.
It's been a long time, Eugene.
Sorry I couldn't come sooner.
Eugene, the Western Front is just
as it was when you were there.
It's still hanging in there, somehow.
You asked me before why I fought, right?
To be honest, I still don't know.
I don't have a reason
to fight the way you did.
But there's one thing I know,
and that's that I...
I promised to take them
all the way to the end,
and a battlefield isn't what I want them
to see when they get there.
The sea...
The thing you wanted
your sister to see someday.
I don't care about seeing it myself.
But I want them to see it.
I think if I can show them something new,
something they've never seen before...
That will be enough of a
reason to fight for now.
I'll come back.
And when I do, I'll tell you about
something you've never seen before.
Marcel.
Nina puts them there.
Eugene's little sister.
She keeps writing letters
to her dead brother.
It's my fault.
Wait!
Why do you just accept it?
It was me!
These letters... I was the one!
I was the one who made her
write these letters to you!
I was just so angry and frustrated,
but I didn't want to blame myself!
So I pretended it was all your fault.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry!
I need to apologize to you.
And to her.
I...
It's good to see him smiling, huh?
Thank you!
Shin, you're not gonna change
your personal mark?
You don't like it?
I don't mind painting it.
But it's a bit of a bad omen...
This is a weird thing to say,
but do you really need
to carry it anymore?
Maybe you're right.
But it can't be a bad omen
after I've had it for six years.
And I don't think of it as a heavy burden.
Sure, sure.
Looks like you're over some stuff.
That's how it seems to me.
I couldn't say.
But...
I think I can see them off now.
March 20th, Stellar Year 2150
Brother...
It's hard to envision a future
without my brother.
I don't have anything I wish for.
Anything I'm seeking.
I still don't know
what I'm living for.
But...
I'm really going to paint it, okay?
I...
I have people who don't plan
on leaving me behind.
Who said I'm the one
they want by their side.
So... I think I'm okay.
I think I can get there alone.
Thank you.
I know.
I haven't forgotten you.
I...
I'm the Reaper.
I'll fight.
Because with the Legion keeping this world
closed off, I can't make it happen.
For their sake.
And for her.
December 26th, Stellar Year 2149
It's thanks to you
that I was able to come back.
I won't forget.
I've returned, Father.
A Legion offensive began on the night
of the Revolution Festival.
Many of my comrades fought, as did I.
Many people of the 86th district
answered my call and fought with us.
I won't forget.
But the Republic is gone.
It took only a week.
We still managed
to keep a defense line going,
and after two months passed, rescue came.
From far to the east, past Legion-held
territory and our own borders.
They—the Giad Federacy—
already knew about the oppression
and slaughter of the Eighty-Six.
The survivors of the 86th district were saved,
and any one of them who wants to
can become a Federacy citizen.
The awful things have all stopped.
The rescue forces remain here,
providing us a modicum of support, but...
Hey, he got more than I did!
Do your jobs.
Can't you coloreds treat us equally?
How did it end up like this?
"There can be no punishment for a citizenry
that's not aware of its crimes."
Is Uncle right, Father?
Colonel Milizé?
Is that...
Ignore it, please.
I see.
As you know, it was the brave soldiers
of the Federacy, equipped with the latest weaponry,
who valiantly pushed back the battle lines
and retook the 1st District,
where we find ourselves today. Correct?
Yes.
The Federacy has requested
that we send an officer to help them
break the stalemate north of District 1
and retake the land stolen by the Legion.
I'm told you've volunteered
to lead the unit assigned to this task.
Is that correct?
It is correct.
As your superior officer,
I knew you'd agree!
I feel the same!
Good luck out there!
So you're going to the Federacy, then?
Yup.
You're not surprised?
After all that's happened?
If something like that could surprise me,
I would've ditched you long ago.
Ever since that day,
you've just been full of surprises.
I've had a lifetime's worth
of surprises already.
Why? Is that possible?
What is it?
This RAID device the Federacy made!
For some reason,
it has the same design as the Republic.
Is it chance?
No, no way in hell it's chance.
What do you mean?
The Federation made it,
but it's got our tech in it!
You couldn't do this without help
from a living Eighty-Six.
But I can't imagine any Eighty-Six making contact
with the Federacy before the Legion offensive...
Seriously...
Sorry.
Well, I guess the answers
will be waiting for us there.
Annette, why do you have
a Federacy RAID device?
'Cause I volunteered.
I'm being sent as a technology officer.
I'm going to the Federacy, too.
When you said you were going
to do everything you could until the end,
I stopped feeling as though
nothing I did would matter.
It's not just me.
The others too, I think.
So, if you're using a Para-RAID,
I'll have to go with you.
We're together again, Lena!
Yeah!
Oh jeez, Annette!
I'm sorry.
We're still putting things together.
Unit Roster
But this...
It's not that we don't respect
your talents, Colonel Milizé.
March 12th, Stellar Year 2150
You and the Eighty-Six survived
the Legion offensive.
We're glad to have an officer like you.
Thank you.
I'll do my best until the very end.
I'll see you in the Federacy, then.
I can buy you time, if nothing else.
It's time for you to be crushed, Lena,
as you watch your naïve dreams
shatter against reality.
Uncle, give me just a bit more time.
Until my dream shatters.
Welcome, welcome!
We've been waiting for you,
Bloody Regina.
Now, let's not waste any time.
There's a place I want to show you.
March 20th, Stellar Year 2150
I won't forget.
I won't forget!
I won't forget...
I'll fight... until I reach
the place they reached...
The place that can be found only by those
who kept going to the very end.
To keep fighting...
To live life to the fullest.
Keep them safe.
I saw her too, actually, then.
I don't remember it well, though.
I can't imagine the look on his face.
They say there's a black cat with her.
If only it were Kitty, right?
Right?
This?
What about this?
This is her!
Theo, cut it out!
That won't happen with Shin!
The two of them aren't like that!
And I've known him longer!
So she's even more
of a little sister than me!
Victory's mine!
Theo!
The perfect boy-meets-girl!
Beep beep.
Beep!
I'll surprise him, too!
What was it? "Bloody Regina"?
Yuck.
Is that how it looks to you?
Will she recognize us?
I hope she does.
But if she doesn't,
that might be fun, too.
I'm sorry I'm late, Mr. President.
No, time spent remembering
someone lost is time well spent.
Now, let me introduce you
to your new team.
Right now?
Yes.
Hey, is that really her?
I'm sure a lot's happened.
You got that right.
I am Colonel Vladilena Milizé
of the San Magnolia Republic.
It's an honor to meet you
for the first time.
This isn't the first time we've met.
It's the first time
we've seen each other, though.
It's been a long time,
Handler One.
I am a Captain in the Giad Federacy,
and the former combat commander
of Spearhead Squadron,
Shinei Nouzen.
Shin...
Kitty!
Machiavelli!
Blackie!
Whitey!
You really are a fool, huh?
Raiden!
Is this us?
Theo!
Thank you for the cat.
Anju!
I'm glad you're alive!
Kurena!
How about we take a photo
to remember today?
That's a great idea!
I followed you for so long.
I know.
I've finally caught up.
You have.
From now on...
I'll fight with you.